[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Throughout this course we have evaluated classifiers in one key way.
خلال هذه الدورة التدريبية، قمنا بتقييم المصنفات بطريقة رئيسية واحدة.
We measured error or the accuracy of that classifier.
قمنا بقياس خطأ هذا المصنف أو دقته.
But it turns out that for many real world applications, error or
ولكن اتضح أنه في العديد من التطبيقات الواقعية،
accuracy is not great measure to try to understand
الخطأ أو الدقة ليسا مقياسًا هامًا في محاولة فهم
whether classifier is doing the right thing for you.
ما إذا كان المصنف يقوم بالشيء المناسب.
And in this module, we're going to talk about precision recall,
وفي هذه الوحدة، سنتحدث عن استدعاء الدقة،
which is a really cool, very simple way to evaluate classifiers that captures
وهي طريقة رائعة جدًا وبسيطة جدًا لتقييم المصنفات حيث تلتقط
something that's needed for a wide range of applications.
الأشياء المطلوبة في مجموعة واسعة من التطبيقات.
And we'll use a cool,
وسنستخدم تطبيقًا رائعًا ومسليًّا،
fun application as a kind of running example throughout the module.
كنوع من الأمثلة على مدار الوحدة.
So here's the idea.
ها هي الفكرة.
Let's say I have a restaurant and I have a goal.
لنفترض أن لدي مطعمًا ولدي هدفًا.
I want to increase the number of guests,
وهو زيادة عدد الضيوف،
the number of people, coming to my restaurant by 30%.
أو عدد الأشخاص الذين يترددون على المطعم، بنسبة 30 ٪.
And I say, I'm going to do a cool advertising campaign to do that.
ثم أفكر بعمل حملة إعلانية عصرية لتحقيق هذا الهدف.
But nobody wants to just get those ads in the mail or
لكن لا أحد يرغب في الحصول على تلك الإعلانات في البريد
spam email as their advertising campaign.
أو رسائل البريد الإلكتروني العشوائية كحملة إعلانية.
So I want to be innovative, I want to be authentic about my advertising campaign.
لذلك أريد أن أكون مبتكرًا، أريد المصداقية في حملتي الإعلانية.
And the way that I want to be authentic is that when I use the voice of my customers
والطريقة التي أريد بها تحقيق تلك المصداقية هي الاستعانة برأي عملائي
to talk about how great the restaurant is.
للحديث عن مدى روعة المطعم.
So when I'm looking at customer reviews, and then I find great things in there,
ثم سأطلع على مراجعات العملاء، لأعثر على الآراء الرائعة،
great nuggets, to be able to tell everyone about how great my restaurant is.
أو المقاطع الرائعة، لأكون قادرًا على إخبار الجميع مدى روعة مطعمي.
So I want to find great quotes,
لذلك أريد العثور على الاقتباسات الرائعة،
key positive sentences that describe amazing things about my restaurant.
الجمل الإيجابية الرئيسية التي تصف أشياء مدهشة عن مطعمي.
And may even find some spokespeople that are really eloquent,
وقد أجد بعض المتحدثين الرسميين الذين يمتلكون البلاغة،
they explain really well what they love about my restaurant.
التي تجعلهم يشرحون جيدًا ما يحبون في مطعمي.
So that's my goal.
هذا هو هدفي.
And so, I might do that automatically by taking the restaurant reviews and
وقد أفعل ذلك تلقائيًا من خلال مراجعات المطعم
posting key sentences or key things that people are saying on my website.
ونشر الجمل الرئيسية أو الآراء الرئيسية التي يقولها الناس على موقع الويب الخاص بي.
So that anybody who lands there can see the latest greatest of what's being said.
بحيث يمكن لأي شخص زائر أن يرى أروع وأحدث ما يقال.
So I want to do a lot of these restaurant reviews, and
أريد أن أفعل الكثير من مراجعات المطعم المثيلة،
I want to automate a lot of that process.
أرغب في جعل الكثير من هذه العمليات تلقائية.
So I want to do it.
أريد فعل ذلك.
So just like we described in the first course in this specialization, we're
ومثلما وصفنا في الدورة الأولى في هذا التخصص
going to take the restaurant reviews, and we're going to split them into sentences.
سنأخذ مراجعات المطعم، وسنقوم بتقسيمها إلى جمل.
So for every sentence, some are positive about my restaurant,
ولكل جملة، بعضها إيجابي عن مطعمي،
some are negative, I want to be able to evaluate.
وبعضها سلبي، أريد أن أكون قادراً على التقييم.
So for example, if the sentence says,
إذن، على سبيل المثال، إذا كانت الجملة هي،
easily the best sushi in Seattle, that's my input xi.
"أفضل سوشي في سياتل"، هذا هو مدخل xi.
And when I feed that for the sentence sentiment classifier and
وعندما أدخل ذلك في المصنف العاطفي للجملة
get an output y hat I which is either positive sentiment or negative sentiment.
سأحل على المخرج y hat i إما بشعور إيجابي أو بشعور سلبي.
And I want to do that for every sentence in every review that I get.
وأريد أن أفعل ذلك في كل جملة وفي كل مراجعة أحصل عليها.
And, in fact, I might even do that in real time.
بل قد أفعل ذلك في الوقت الفعلي.
Every time a new review comes in, I'm going to feed it through this classifier
في كل مرة تأتي فيها مراجعة جديدة، سأقوم بإدخالها في نموذج المصنف
model, and start to predict y hat i has been positive for some sentences.
والبدء في توقع y hat i إيجابي لبعض الجمل.
These are the great ones, the ones I want to show off,
والبحث عن الجمل الجميلة التي أرغب في عرضها،
the ones I want to talk about.
والتي أريد التحدث عنها.
And then y hat i -1, this is the negative ones, I want to ignore those.
ومن ثم y hat i -1، هي الكلمات السلبية، التي أريد تجاهلها.
So I only care about the positive ones, and
لذلك أنا أهتم فقط بالأشياء الإيجابية
I'm going to do my best to take those positive sentences,
سأبذل قصارى جهدي لاستخراج هذه الجمل الإيجابية،
show them in a way that people really feel, man, my restaurant is awesome.
التي تبين لهم مدى روعة المطعم، بحيث تجعلهم يروجون له.
I'm going to go there for sushi.
وبحيث يصبح أول ما يخطر ببالهم عند الرغبة في تناول السوشي.
So how do I find those positive sentences?
إذن، كيف أجد تلك الجمل الإيجابية؟
I am going to do a sentiment classifier.
سأقوم بعمل تصنيف عاطفي.
How do I know the sentiment classifier is really good, I can trust it,
كيف أتأكد من جودة المصنّف العاطفي، وكيف يمكنني الوثوق به،
I can put those sentences on my website without having to check
يمكنني وضع هذه الجمل على موقع الويب الخاص بي دون الاضطرار إلى التحقق
every time a sentence goes up?
في كل مرة تظهر فيها جملة مختلفة؟
This is the key point.
هذه هي النقطة الأساسية.
We are talking about automating machine learning.
نحن نتحدث عن جعل التعلم الآلي تلقائي.
You have to really trust the machine learning model.
عليك أن تثق حقًا في نموذج التعلم الآلي.
So if I give you a particular, say, accuracy, is that enough trust for
ﻟذا، إذا أعطيتكم دقة معينة، ﻓﮭل يعني ذلك وجود الثقة الكافية
me to just automatically feed reviews into something that shows up in my website?
لإدخال المراجعات تلقائيًا لتظهر في موقعي على الويب؟
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]